<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<content>
  <assignment name="Prerequisites">
    <exercise name="Overview">
      Welcome to the Right Career Concept Overview. The objective is to provide an overview of the Right Career and Whole Person concepts.
      
          •	Create meaning and passion
          •	Be your best
          •	Fuel your “economic engine”
        
      <image source="overviewVenn.jpg"></image>
      
      To **launch the video** click on the __paragraph heading__ below. This will launch ##Windows Media Player## and a presentation by Don will begin on that topic. When the presentation finishes you can close Windows Media Player and then the Tab and you will return to this page.
      
      <video source="MyRC-1-RightCareerConcepts.wmv"></video>
    </exercise>

    <exercise name="Program Approach">
      You may identify your Right Career or Careers after completing only three of the Insights Assignments. It just all falls together and you say “Yes, that is what I should be doing”.

      This can happen no matter which of the two approaches described below, College Course or Cafeteria, you choose.
    </exercise>

    <exercise name="Program Content">
      The content is composed of a Prerequisite Assignment, six Insights Assignments and a Capstone Assignment. Below are short descriptions of each Assignment and the exercises within that Assignment.
    </exercise>
  </assignment>
  
  <assignment name="Future">
    <exercise name="Visualize Yourself at Age 30">
      You want to describe your situation at your 30th birthday. One way I suggest doing this is actually putting you at that 30th birthday party. Better yet make it a whole 30th Birthday weekend – you have the party on Saturday night and you have a bunch of your long term friends coming to visit you for the weekend. Who would those long term friends be that would come to spend the weekend. During that time what types of things would they be asking you and what types of things would you tell them about your life. What if you had not seen one of your long term friends in 5 years – how would you describe your life to him/her?
    </exercise>

    <exercise name="Work Backwards">
      Now pick one category, e.g. Financial, Personal Relationship, Family, Career. With that one category you will work backwards from your Ultimate End Result (age 30) to your Intermediate End Result #3 (age 27) to your Intermediate End Result #2 (age 24) to your Intermediate End Result #1 (age 22). You can pick any ages for your Intermediate End Results that make sense for your life. The above are just to give you a starting point. The “Work Backwards” portion of the assignment will probably take you about 1/2 to 1 hour.
    </exercise>

    <exercise name="Structural Tension">
      Now use the Structural Tension idea and create the objectives (try to keep it around 5 objectives) that would get you from your Current Reality to your Intermediate End Result #1. This portion of the assignment will probably take you about 1/2 hour.
    </exercise>
  </assignment>

  <assignment name="Self">
    <exercise name="Strong Interest Inventory">
      Keep in mind that the Strong Inventory measures interests, not skills or abilities. The report is summarizing what you said in the assessment – so this is what you said interests you. I have found people often think these interests were created by the system, they were not, they are yours. The results can help guide you toward rewarding careers, work activities, education programs, and leisure activities—all based on your interests.
    </exercise>

    <exercise name="Strong and Myers-Briggs">
      You have already taken this assessment and received the Strong Interest Inventory and Myers-Briggs Type Indicator Career Report (with Strong Profile) Report. The last part of this report is titled Strong and MBTI Career Report. It has 13 pages. Here is an example:
    </exercise>

    <exercise name="Add to Insights">
      If you remember from the previous exercises, there are five MyRightCareer Insights files: one for “Be Your Best”, one for “Meaning and Passion”, one for “Fuel Your Economic Engine”, one for “Right Opportunity” and one for “Whole Person”. Each file has a section for you to record your insights after you complete each exercise. By the end of the MyRightCareer Program you will have accumulated a lot of insights that will assist you in identifying your Right Career and preparing your Sales Story.
    </exercise>
  </assignment>

  <assignment name="Past">
    <exercise name="List All Accomplishments">
      You need to create a list of Accomplishments from elementary school to today.
    </exercise>

    <exercise name="List Top Accomplishments">
      In this Step you need to decide two things about your list of Accomplishments:

        • Those you really liked doing
        • Those you didn’t like doing, but still did

      Normally you put Accomplishments on your resume that you know other people will find impressive. It doesn’t matter if you enjoyed doing them or not. You are looking for all the things that will sell you to others. You are looking for the things that are “hot” at this moment in time. You are creating a special resume for that target company.

      You clearly will probably have Accomplishments on your resume that you did not enjoy doing, we all do. But you would not openly say you didn’t enjoy doing it, which we are going to do here.
    </exercise>

    <exercise name="Document Insights">
      In this Step you need to document the insights you have gained from creating a list of your Accomplishments, deciding which ones you really liked doing and which ones you did not like doing. We suggest your Insights document have three sections:

        • General
        • Liked
        • Didn’t Like
    </exercise>
  </assignment>

  <assignment name="Strengths">
    <exercise name="Skills">
      One of the more **important** elements in identifying your Right Career is recognizing the skills you have that you ##really## enjoy using. If you enjoy doing something you will usually do it really well, allowing you to Be Your Best. Those skills will most likely be ones for which you have a Passion. They may also be ones which have Meaning for you.
      
      Click @@On-Line Skills Help@http://www.onetonline.org/help/online/skills@@
      
      The __Skills Search__ function is designed to help you use your skill set to identify occupations for exploration. You select a set of skills from six broad groups of skills to create your customized skill list.
      
      Begin by selecting skills from one or more of the six skill groups identified: Basic Skills, Complex Problem Solving Skills, Resource Management Skills, Social Skills, Systems Skills, and Technical Skills. Start by selecting as many skills as you have or plan to acquire.
    </exercise>
  </assignment>
</content>