<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <page>
    <><>
	<steps>
	  <task name="Exercise Strategy">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    One of the purposes of the Alpha Program is to collect a group of examples to assist students who will use the MyRightCareer Program in the future. As you are witnessing the Program relies heavily on examples as the way to communicate how to do an exercise.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    The long term goal is to have comprehensive set of exercises:
		  </p>
		  <bullet title="All of the target markets:">
		    Undergraduate Students (freshman, sophomores, juniors and seniors), Graduate Students and Just Graduated
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="Gender Mix:">
		    maybe 60% female and 40% male, which is the typical college campus mix
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="Degree Discipline Mix:">
		    Career Oriented (e.g. Engineering and Business) and Academic Oriented (e.g. Liberal Arts and Sciences). Historically college graduates’ disciplines are about 60% career oriented and 40% academic oriented. I plan to have the example mix probably 60% academic oriented because they are more likely to want to identify a Career than students who have already chosen a Career oriented discipline.
		  </bullet>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="1) Pick a Stage Name">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    Your exercise will not be put on the MyRightCareer Web site using your real name. You should pick a name you would like us to use. Maybe it is one you would use if you decided to be an actor, singer, writer, etc.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="2) Send your completed exercises to Don">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    Send all of your completed material for this exercise to Don@My-Right-Career.com: Age 30 End Result (your Vision), Work Backwards, Structural Tension and Insights.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    He will review it and remove anything he feels would disclose your personal identity, e.g. names of friends, high school name, college name. He will conform the file names, headings, etc to the standards used on all the other examples (if you used the templates this will not require much work). He will append your “stage name” to the front of all of the files.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="3) Review and comment on Don's Exercise files">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    Don will send you the proposed exercise files. You should review them and suggest any changes you would like made, e.g. drop this information, reword this information.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="Don will load your Example on the Examples page">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    At the minimum your example will appear on the examples page, “Woody – Just Graduated”. Individual pieces of your example may be integrated into the Full Instructions.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	</steps>
 </page>