<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <page>
    <name>Step 0 - Introduction-Begin at End</name>
    <steps>
      <task name="Begin at the End Concept">
        <text>
          <p>
            So what is the Begin at the End approach? Robert Fritz discovered it when he studied great artists. He found they used this technique to visualize their end result of playing the piano in Carnegie hall and working backwards to their current reality of playing piano in the 4th grade. They then created structural tension between their current reality and a realistic first step. Great athletic coaches use this to visualize winning the league championship and working backwards to their current reality of having just finished a losing season. They then created structural tension between their current reality and a realistic first step. They realized it they did not make it to that first step they were not going to make it to their end result.
          </p>
          <p>
            In both cases starting with their current reality (playing piano in the 4th grade or coming off of a losing season) seems so over whelming people are often stuck and can not make any progress. The secret to these successful people is their ability to Visualize the End Result and Work Backwards and then start with some small steps.
          </p>
        </text>
      </task>
      <task name="Instructions">
        <text>
          <heading>Welcome to the Begin at the End Exercise</heading>
          <p>
            Click on the link above to see a 5 minute video where Don explains your Assignment via some examples.
          </p>
          <p>
            Note: If you are using a Mac you will need to install Flip4Mac, the official Windows Media Player on the Mac, so you can play Windows Media files (.wma and .wmv) and view Windows Media content using a Web browser. You only need the Free player. Click Flip4Mac.
          </p>
          <p>
            At the conclusion of the video close the Windows Media Player, then close the page it was running in and you will return to this page.
          </p>
          <p>
            There are two major sections to the these instructions. In the first section you will learn about the basic “Begin at the End” approach. This approach is applicable to a lot of aspects of your life besides your career. I have used it very successfully in business. It is used by many successful coaches and athletes.
          </p>
          <p>
            In the second section you will go to a unique page for each step in the Assignment: 1) Visualize Yourself at Age 30, 2) Work Backward, 3) Create a Structural Tension document, 4) document your MyRightCareer Insights, 5) Provide feedback, 6) Discuss your completed exercise with your Facilitator and 7) Become an Example. None of the steps take longer than one hour. Steps 1 through 4 will probably take you about 4 hours.
          </p>
        </text>
      </task>
      <task name="Resources to help you">
        <text>
          <p>
            <bold>Examples:</bold>
            One of the best ways to do this exercise is to look at how others have done the exercise. There is an exercise from Edward in all of the Assignments and it is the most complete exercise. You do not have to have your exercise be as complete as his, but it is useful as an example. The other exercises are more representative of what a typical college student would do. The examples can be found on the Begin at the End Examples page in the Sub Navigation section on the right hand side of this page.
          </p>
          <p>
            <bold>Templates:</bold>
            The examples also serve as templates. You can download them in their native format, mostly Word, and then use their structure, substituting your own information. They can be found on the Begin at the End Templates page in the Sub Navigation section on the right hand side of this page.
          </p>
          <p>
            <bold>Video:</bold>
            For those of you who learn better by listening to a presentation, instead of reading instructions, you can watch the Welcome video again.
          </p>
        </text>
      </task>
    </steps>
  </page>