<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <page>
    <name>Step 3 - Create Structural Tension</name>
	<text>
	  <p>
	    Now use the Structural Tension idea and create the objectives (try to keep it around 5 objectives) that would get you from your Current Reality to your Intermediate End Result #1. This portion of the assignment will probably take you about 1/2 hour.
	  </p>
	</text>
	<steps>
	  <task name="A) Write Your Structural Tension Document">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    If you click on <link URL = "http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Casey-StructuralTension.pdf">Casey’s Structural Tension</link> you will get a pdf file of how Casey created a Structural Tension diagram between her Current Reality (summer between her Sophomore & Junior year) and her Intermediate End Result #1 (age 22 = graduation from college). It shows her objectives for those two years.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    If you click on <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Madison-StructuralTension.pdf">Madison’s Structural Tension</link> you will get a pdf file of how Madison created a Structural Tension diagram.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    If you click on <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Don-StructuralTension.pdf">Edward’s Structural Tension</link> you will get a pdf file of how Edward created Structural Tension diagram between his Current Reality (start of his senior year) and his Intermediate End Result #1 (end of his senior year). Because of the nature of his 3 potential career paths he had to make his Intermediate End Result #1 be closer in than suggested.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="Add your Structural Tension Thoughts">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    At the end of Casey, Madison and Edward’s Structural Tension documents you will see a section titled “Insights”. In that section they provide the insights they gained by doing this exercise. For example Casey’s Insights are:
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Doing this Structural Tension exercise sure brought me back to reality. It made me focus on the fact that I am not going to be a Director unless I reach my first objective “I am an intern at either one of the top clothing design companies or top marketing professionals at one of the top clothing companies.”
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    When I came up with the list of five things I need to accomplish in the next two years it made me realize I have a lot of hard work in front of me. But I can now see it can lead to something great. I actually don’t know if I really want to pursue that exact path but I think those 5 objectives are the right ones for me because I am going to do something in that general area.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Madison had these insights:
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    By focusing on these small steps, it will make the process of attaining my first intermediate end result a lot more manageable. I know now that I must work hard to attain these goals, in order to ultimately achieve my dream.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Edward also has insights at the end of his Structural Tension document. Rather than showing them in total here is a summary:
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    If I took either the Business or Legal path I had to make that decision by January of my senior year, i.e in only 6 months. This was because they both required me to go to graduate school and I would need to apply to either an MBA Program or a Law school by then. Even before than I need to be doing preparation work on those two paths. I was clearly behind in making my career decision.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Now you need to add your own Insights to your Structural Tension document.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	</steps>
  </page>