<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <page>
    <name>Step 5 - Discuss with your Adviser-End</name>
	<text>
	  <p>
	    Now it is time to discuss your results with your Adviser/Facilitator. You may have been communicating with them along the way so they may already know some of what you have done, e.g. you might have shared you Age 30 Vision. But assuming you have not shared anything here are the suggested items to share and discuss:
	  </p>
	</text>
	<steps>
	  <task name="A) Discuss Content Issues">
	    <text>
	      <p>
		    These first items are content oriented issues:
		  </p>
		  <bullet title="Age 30 Vision Document:">
		    (If you are currently 25 then your Age 30 Vision will probably be an Age 35 Vision)
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="Work Backwards: Age 22 Intermediate End Result #1:">
		    (This is assuming you are currently an undergrad and you will graduate at age 22).
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="Structural Tension: Age Now vs. Age 22 Structural Tension Document:">
		    What are you going to focus on in the next few months that will move you closer to where you want to be upon graduation.
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="MyRightCareer Insights Documents:">
		    This is the most important set of documents you have to discuss. They should have taken all of their findings in this exercise and placed them in the appropriate document – Be Your Best, Meaning/Passion, Economic Engine, Right Career and Whole Person. They will form the foundation for the identification of your Right Opportunity in the Capstone Project.
		  </bullet>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="B) Discuss Process Issues">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		  </p>
		  <bullet title="Schedule:">
		    You now have an idea of how long it took to do one Assignment vs. the estimated time. You and your Adviser may want to revise your schedule.
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="Adviser Review Process:">
		    You have just finished your 1st review, maybe the two of you want to do it differently in the future.
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="Anything else you want to discuss:">
		    Who knows what has come up in doing this first Assignment.
		  </bullet>
		</text>
	  </task>
	</steps>
  </page>