<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <page>
    <name>Step 4 - MyRightCareer Insights-End</name>
	<steps>
	  <task name="Overview">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    There are five MyRightCareer Insights files, one for each of the circles in the Right Career Venn diagram: “Be Your Best”, “Meaning & Passion”, “Fuel Your Economic Engine” and “Right Career”. There is another for the Whole Person. Each file has a section for you to record your insights after you complete each exercise. It is better to write down as many insights as you can, even if you don’t think they are exactly relevant. It is easy to forget things in a long program. 
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    These files are the most important files you are creating. By the end of the MyRightCareer Program you will have accumulated a lot of insights that will assist you in identifying your Right Career and preparing your Sales Story.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="Examples">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    MyRightCareer Insights These five documents are examples of the insights Casey obtained from completing all the exercises: Begin at the End, Autobiography, Accomplishments, Personality, Interests, Strengths, Skills, Stories, Drivers, How Will You Measure Your Life and Fuel Your Economic Engine. From these examples you can see how insights were added with every exercise. Some of the insights might be the same, just stated in a slightly different way. Or you can have the exact same insights used in multiple circles. In fact that is what you want to see. Then you start to pick up some themes. Click on the links below to see the documents.
		  </p>
		  <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Casey-MyRC-BeYourBest-Insights_Final.pdf">Casey’s “Be Your Best” Insights</link>
		  <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Casey-MyRC-MeaningPassion-Insights_Final.pdf">Casey’s “Meaning & Passion” Insights</link>
		  <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Casey-MyRC-EconomicEngine-Insights_Final.pdf">Casey’s “Economic Engine” Insights</link>
		  <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Casey-MyRC-RightCareeer-Insights_Final.pdf">Casey’s “Right Career” Insights</link>
		  <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Casey-MyRC-WholePerson-Insights_Final.pdf">Casey’s “Whole Person” Insights</link>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="Create your MyRightCareer Insights Documents">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    Templates for these files can be found on the Begin at the End Templates page. You can use these templates to create your own files and begin filling out your insights. You are only adding insights for the Begin at the End exercise. One of the simplest ways of doing this is to copy/paste from the files you created in this exercise. Error on the side of including too much information in the MyRightCareer Insights files. It will be easier to delete this information later than to go back to this exercise and try to recreate it when you are working on your Capstone Project.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Take your existing MyRightCareer Insights documents and add the insights you have gained from this exercise. Be sure to add insights to each of the documents: 
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Keep these five files somewhere you will not lose them. You are going to adding to them as part of each exercise.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	</steps>
  </page>