<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <page>
    <name>Step 1 - Visualize Yourself at Age 30</name>
	<steps>
	  <task name="Visualization Concept">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    You want to describe your situation at your 30th birthday. One way I suggest doing this is actually putting you at that 30th birthday party. Better yet make it a whole 30th Birthday weekend – you have the party on Saturday night and you have a bunch of your long term friends coming to visit you for the weekend. Who would those long term friends be that would come to spend the weekend. During that time what types of things would they be asking you and what types of things would you tell them about your life. What if you had not seen one of your long term friends in 5 years – how would you describe your life to him/her?
		  </p>
		  <p>
			I am asking you to truly visualize yourself at age 30. If you are artistic you may want to draw some pictures of your 30th birthday party and other events surrounding your 30th birthday. If you are like me and can’t draw or paint, you may want to download some clip art.
		  </p>
		  <p>
			With all that art you could create a Vision Board. Edward’s Dream Board below was created with O Dream Board. I am sure most of you can do a more artistic job than Edward did, but it does communicate most of what he has in his Word document. 
		  </p>
		  <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Edward-Age30_VisionBoard.jpg">
		    Edward's Age 30 Vision Board
		  </link>
		  <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Edward-EndResultAge30.pdf">
		    Edward's End Result in Words
		  </link>
		  <p>
		    The O Dream Board is available for free at <link URL="http://www.oprah.com/dreamboard/index.html">Oprah.com.</link> I am not endorsing their product, just providing them as an example.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Another method of creating a Vision Board is to cut out photo’s and paste them on a big poster board, You can also write and draw on the poster board.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    A great resource to help you do this is a friend who knows you well. This is an exercise that lends itself to brainstorming. The two of you can spend an hour talking about your vision of yourself at age 30. Together you will come up with something better than you will by yourself.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    The “Visualize the End Result” portion of the assignment will probably take you from 1 to 2 hours.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="A) Visualize your Whole Person at Age 30">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    This exercise allows you to accomplish something very important – paint a picture, using the “Whole Person” parameters, of your life at age 30. Click on <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Whole-Person.pdf">Whole Person</link> to see a chart depicting the Whole Person concept. It was explained in the Right Career Course you took in the Prerequisites Assignment (you did take that course didn’t you?). You are more than just your Career, you have all of the other elements surrounding your Career. There are a lot more things to consider when choosing your Right Career than just the jobs you will have, e.g. where you want to live, your personal relationships and your family. For example what if when you are 30 and you are only willing to be living and working in California. Or you may only be willing to work somewhere that allows you to live in San Francisco and not commute more than 30 minutes. As you later go through the process of deciding on your Right Career these Whole Person parameters will be very important to understand. By fast forwarding to age 30 you can see if you have some Whole Person issues that will end up heavily influencing your career choices.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Click on <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Madison-EndResultAge30.pdf">Madison’s End Result</link> and you will see an example of the document you will end up creating.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Here are some standard variables you can start with, but customize the list for your unique situation.
		  </p>
		  <heading>Whole Person Elements</heading>
		  <p>
		    At age 30 there will be more to your life than just your job (career). This exercise also allows you to complete the picture with other “Whole Person” parameters.
		  </p>
		  <bullet title="Personal Items, e.g.:">
		    Personal Relationship (e.g., single, living with someone or married), Immediate Family (e.g. no kids, one kid or two kids), Extended Family (e.g., emotionally close to them, estranged from them, live close by), Friends (e.g. ones from high school & college, new ones from work), Location (e.g. San Francisco, NYC, Europe, in a city, in the countryside), Residence (e.g. house, condo, apartment), Your Health (e.g. still playing soccer, better shape than now, better shape than other 30 year old’s)
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="Work Related Items,e.g.:">
		    Type Organization (e.g. , Fortune 100, Early Stage Hi Tech, Non-Profit, Education), Social work environment (lots of young like minded people, serious top tier firm), Physical work environment (Google type, Wall Street type), Commute (out of home, less than 30 minutes, by train to city)
		  </bullet>
		  <p>
		    You can also use the categories in <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/WholePerson-Examples-V3.pdf">Whole Person Examples</link> as a template. It provides sample sentences you could use to describe your situation at Age 30.
		  </p>
		  <heading>Whole Person Examples</heading>
		  <p>
		    Below are different examples of how people visualized themselves at Age 30 on some Whole Person parameters:
		  </p>
		  <bullet title="Married:">
		    This person visualized themselves being married when they were age 30. They wanted to live together two years before getting married.
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="Married and Buying a House or Condo:">
		    This person visualized themselves buying a house by the time they are 30. They also visualized themselves being married by that time as well. But they are determined to own a house, or condo, by age 30 whether or not they are married.
		  </bullet>
		  <bullet title="Married and Having your 1st child:">
		    This person visualizes themselves having a family with their 1st child being born when they are are 30 and other children to follow soon after. They want to have been married for two years before starting the child bearing process to ensure they have a stable marriage.
		  </bullet>
		  <heading>What if you are out of College?</heading>
		  <p>
		    Age 30 was chosen because it is far enough enough from the typical college student (e.g. Age 21 or Age 22) to allow them to remove themselves from their current situation. Age 30 is also a major milestone.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    If you are already out of school than you want to use an age about 7 to 10 years in the future. Carolyn is 25 and she used age 35. Click on <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/Elizabeth-EndResult-Age30.pdf">Elizabeth’s End Result</link> to see how she visualizes herself at Age 35.
		  </p>
		  <heading>Write Your Age 30 Vision Document</heading>
		  <p>
		    If you click on <link URL="www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/Template-EndResult-Age30.doc">End Result Word Template</link> you will get a Word file with a lot of headings you can use to create your own Age 30 End Result document. If you would like to use Casey’s document as your template click on <link URL="www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Casey-EndResult-Age30.doc">Casey’s End Result</link> and you will get a Word file of Casey’s End Result description.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Even though Casey, Madison and Edward’s examples all have a career element to them they still are mainly a definition of their Whole Person, so they are good examples for you to use.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="B) Optional Exercise - Visualize your Career at Age 30">
	    <p>
		  I know what you are thinking – “The purpose of the MyRightCareer Program is to help me identify my Right Career, so why am I being asked to visualize my career at age 30?” This is a totally optional part of this exercise. If you don’t have any idea of what your career will be at age 30 then skip this part of the exercise.
		</p>
		<p>
		  Here are some reasons you may want to attempt to visualize a career at age 30: 1) You might already have some ideas and the MyRightCareer Program will allow you to validate if any or all of them are good ideas, 2) You just might want to try out a career idea to see how it feels when surrounded by all the other Whole Person parameters (e.g. When I am 30 I am a lawyer working in the White House, living in Georgetown, I am so busy I barely have time to date, but this is so exciting, etc), 3) By thinking a long way out in time it might help you think of some careers you would like to be doing at that time, 4) It might help you think of some careers, or things, you would NOT like to be doing at that time (e.g. I don’t want to do what my Dad has been doing for the last 30 years or I don’t want to be working in an office) or 5) You might just want to describe some parameters for your career like Harry does below.
		</p>
		<heading>Career Dimensions</heading>
		<p>
		  A simple way to think of a career is it has two dimensions: Function and Industry.
		</p>
		<bullet title="Function, e.g. Sales, Marketing, P/R, Finance:">
		  There is a definition for this dimension and it is called Standard Occupational Classification (SOC). There are 840 Occupations and they are in Major Groups (23), Minor Groups (97) and Broad Group (461). Click on <link URL="http://www.onetonline.org/find/">O*NET Occupations</link> to access a Web site that will allow you to explore the vast range of occupations in a variety of ways, e.g. Job Family (groups of occupations based upon work performed, skills, education, training, and credentials), Career Clusters (occupations in the same field of work that require similar skills), Bright Outlook (occupations which are expected to grow rapidly in the next several years, will have large numbers of job openings, or are new and emerging occupations).
		</bullet>
		<bullet title="Industry, e.g. Manufacturing, Retail, Health Care, Finance, Art/Entertainment:">
		  There is a definition for this dimension and it is called the North American Industry Classification System (NAICS). Every company has a NAICS. Click on <link URL="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">2012 NAICS</link> and you will see a list of the 20 major industry groups. You can click on any of those major industry groups and you will then see the sub industries (maybe 30 more). 
		</bullet>
		<p>
		  While almost every Occupation, or function, exists in every Industry they can be quite different depending on the Industry. For example sales in high tech is different than sales in consumer goods. Sales tends to require a lot of knowledge of the industry and customer. There are roles like Finance have more elements in common across the different industries.
		</p>
		<p>
		  During the remainder of the MyRightCareer Program you will have opportunities to revisit the issue of occupations and industries.
		</p>
		<p>
		  To visualize your career it might be sufficient to only choose one of the two dimensions, e.g.
		</p>
		<bullet title="Function:">
		  I see myself working in marketing.
		</bullet>
		<bullet title="Industry:">
		  I see myself working in the fashion industry.
		</bullet>
		<heading>Career Visualization Examples</heading>
		<p>
		  Below are different examples of how people visualized their careers:
		</p>
		<bullet title="Multiple Majors:">
		  In some ways Edward has not really thought about a career because he has still not settled on a major. This is not an unusual problem for students, especially in today’s economic climate. Edward has three different possible strategies for his major: Engineering (finishing his engineering degree and having that be his terminal major), Business (finishing his engineering degree and then immediately go into an MBA Program) and Legal (finishing his engineering degree and then immediately go to Law school). If you click on Edward’s End Result you will get a pdf file of Edward vision of himself at age 30. It is not hard for Edward to visualize having a technical career given he is about to enter his senior year in engineering school and will soon graduate as an engineer. Edward is using the MyRightCareer Program to decide which of the majors is right for him.
		</bullet>
		<bullet title="Multiple Career Ideas:">
		  Carolyn is three years out college and has just turned 25. She see herself at Age 35 in one of three careers: Chief Marketing Officer in a company, Lawyer/Entrepreneur and something in the Health field. Click on <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/Elizabeth-Working_Backwards.pdf">Elizabeth’s Work Backwards</link> to see how she describes her three career possibilities.
		</bullet>
		<bullet title="Very General:">
		  Harry did not have a specific career in mind. Rather he has some parameters, he wanted something that: I enjoy, I am good at, I have passion for, I am helping others (makes me feel positive), I am in charge of my own destiny (no one employer can fire me), I have flexibility to take time off, I have flexibility to work in various locations, and I can work part-time if needed. Harry is going to use the MyRightCareer Program to identify a career that will meet those parameters.
		</bullet>
		<bullet title="Try out a Career Idea:">
		  Madison thinks she wants to have her own business when she is 30. That is a very general idea of a career and can have many different variations. Madison is using the MyRightCareer Program to validate if owning her own business is the right career for her.
		</bullet>
		<bullet title="A Best Guess:">
		  Casey has an idea of what she wants to do as a career. She is not sure that it is exactly her Right Career and is going to use the MyRightCareer Program to validate that choice. If you click on <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Casey-EndResult-Age30.pdf">Casey’s End Result</link> you will get a pdf file showing Casey’s description of her life at Age 30. While she is not so sure about her career choice, she does have some pretty concrete ideas about several Whole Person parameters, e.g. location and personal relationships. Casey is using the MyRightCareer Program to validate her Best Guess and if that turns out to not be true to iterate to another Best Guess.
		</bullet>
		<p>
		  Remember if you don’t have an idea of what career you want then just skip this part of the exercise. The most important part of this exercise is painting a picture of your Whole Person, without your career, at age 30. It will help frame your career decision later in the Program.
		</p>
	  </task>
	  <task name ="C) Add your Age 30 Vision Insights">
	  <p>
	    At the end of Casey, Madison and Edward’s Age 30 Vision documents you will see a section titled “Insights”. In that section they provide the insights they gained by doing this exercise. For example Edward’s Insights are:
	  </p>
	  <p>
	    It was fun to think about the other elements of my life at that time. Some I have thought about, e.g. location (I have wanted to live in California, which means LA to me, for a long time), commute (I worked two summers in big cities and had to commute) and fun (with a salary I know I will be able to do a lot of fun things). But a lot of the others (e.g. personal relationship, kids, friends) I had not given much thought.
	  </p>
	  <p>
	    This has been helpful because I was forced to put down on paper my choice of a major – which of the 3 paths do I want to take. I thought I had made that choice when I was a sophomore. It has been rolling around in my head for the last year, but I have not really been focusing on it. This let me remove myself from my immediate decision and think about what I want my work life to be when I am 30.
	  </p>
	  <p>
	    You now need to add your own Insights at the end of your Age 30 vision document.
	  </p>
	  </task>
	</steps>
  </page>