<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <page>
    <name>Step 2 - Work Backwards</name>
	<steps>
	  <task name="A) Write your Work Backwards Document">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    Now pick one category, e.g. Financial, Personal Relationship, Family, Career. With that one category you will work backwards from your Ultimate End Result (age 30) to your Intermediate End Result #3 (age 27) to your Intermediate End Result #2 (age 24) to your Intermediate End Result #1 (age 22). You can pick any ages for your Intermediate End Results that make sense for your life. The above are just to give you a starting point. The “Work Backwards” portion of the assignment will probably take you about 1/2 to 1 hour.
		  </p>
		  <heading>Whole Person Examples</heading>
		  <p>
		    Below are some examples that use Whole Person parameters to help you write your own document.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    <link URL = "http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/Married-WorkBackwards.pdf"> Married at Age 30</link> This person visualized themselves being married when they were age 30. They wanted to live together two years before getting married.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/House-WorkBackwards.pdf">Married & Buy a House at Age 30</link> This person visualized themselves buying a house by the time they are 30. They also visualized themselves being married by that time as well. But they are determined to own a house, or condo, by age 30 whether or not they are married. This example contains a financial analysis that works backwards from the house they visualize buying at Age 30 to what they must start doing at Age 23.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/Child-WorkBackwards.pdf">Married & 1st Child at Age 30</link> This person visualizes themselves having a family with their 1st child being born when they are are 30 and other children to follow soon after. They want to have been married for two years before starting the child bearing process to ensure they have a stable marriage.
		  </p>
		  <heading>Career Examples</heading>
		  <p>
		    If you chose a career as an end result and want to work backwards from that end point below are some examples that will help you. Casy’s example is also a template you can find on the Template page.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Casey-WorkBackwards.pdf">Casey’s Work Backwards</link> is a pdf file of how Casey worked backwards from her age 30 career idea to age 22, her graduation from college.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Madison-WorkBackwards.pdf">Madison’s Work Backwards</link> is a pdf file of how Madison worked backwards.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Don-WorkBackwards.pdf">Edward’s Work Backwards</link> is a pdf file of how Edward worked backwards for each of his three possible careers. On the second page you will also see how he worked backwards on his personal relationship.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    <link URL="http://www.my-right-career.com/sp-explore/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/Elizabeth-Working_Backwards.pdf">Elizabeth’s Work Backwards</link> is a pdf file of how Elizabeth worked backwards from age 35 to her current age (25). She also worked backwards on her Personal Life. Her document is well done and you could user her format for yours if you have multiple career ideas.
		  </p>
		  <heading>Create your own Work Backwards document</heading>
		  <p>
		    Now you need to create your own Work Backwards document.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	  <task name="B) Add your Work Backwards Insights">
	    <text>
		  <p>
		    The “Work Backwards Insights” portion of the assignment will probably take you about 1/2 to 1 hour.
		  </p>
		  <heading>Whole Person Examples</heading>
		  <p>
		    At the end of the Getting Married, Buying a House or Condo and Having a Baby Work Backwards documents you will see a section titled “Insights”. In that section you will find the insights gained by doing this exercise.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    For example the “Married & Having our 1st Child” example Insights are:
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    I have placed a lot of constraints on myself: wanting to be married for 2 years before having a baby, wanting to live together for 1 year before getting married and wanting to date seriously for 1 year before living together. This backs everything up 4 years. Then you have to add 1 year to actually have a baby and it is 5 years from the time we start dating seriously. What if it takes another year to have our 1st child, it is now 6 years. This only gives me two years to meet the right person.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Another example are the Insights from “Married & Buying a House”:
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    I have to do everything as if I am not going to be married. Or as if my significant other is not going to contribute. I have to start saving when I am 23 if I want to have $50K when I am 30 years old. If my significant other has been saving then we will have more than $50K. I also have to significantly increase my income from age 22 to age 30 – it doubles from $40K to $80K. If my salary doesn’t increase that fast I will end up saving less than $50K.
		  </p>
		  <heading>Career Examples</heading>
		  <p>
		    At the end of Casey, Madison and Edward’s Work Backwards documents you will see a section titled “Insights”. In that section they provide the insights they gained by doing this exercise.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    For example Casey’s Insights are:
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Working backwards was not an easy concept for me. It was easy to define where I wanted to be at age 30, even though I am not sure that is really my Right Career it is still a fun thing to think about. Then I had to think what type of person would that company want to hire as their Director of Marketing & PR. What would I have to have done before I got that job to be a good candidate? I decided they would either want someone who was already a Director, but in another small company in the same area, or they would want someone from a large well known company. I also decided they would want someone who had managed people. So I gave myself that resume. Then I had to decide how would I have gotten to be a manager in a large well known company? I assumed I would have to have worked my way up from the bottom by being very successful so I joined them out of college. It was fun and a learning experience to build up my resume this way.
		  </p>
		  <heading>Add your own Insights</heading>
		  <p>
		    Now you need to add your own Insights to your Work Backwards document.
		  </p>
		  <p>
		    Working backwards has the benefit of introducing reality to your End Result. If your professional End Result is to be the VP of Marketing for Facebook by age 30 working backwards will probably show you that is quite a challenge. If your personal End Result is having 3 kids by the time you are 30 it will show you to not wait until you are 27 to get married.
		  </p>
		</text>
	  </task>
	</steps>
  </page>